Jessie Albarian

Hello! I'm Jessie.

I am a professional freelance software developer and designer who has experience with websites, apps, UX/UI, branding, and print design. But I don't just build products, I create solutions. I dive deep into my client's goals, and my work revolves around these in order to help the overall success of their business. I am an artist at heart with a logical mind, so I work on projects with both my creativity and problem solving mindset.

Contact



720-217-5217



albarian.jess@gmail.com



jessiealbarian.com



linkedin.com/in/jessalbarian



@jessalbarian



github.com/jessalbarian

Places I've Been



Skills and Languages

iOS Development - Swift Android Development - Java Illustrator / Photoshop Shopify - Liquid Prototyping / Wireframes WordPress - PHP JavaScript / jQuery WIX, Squarespace Angular 1 & 2 HTML / CSS Sass C++ Python C# SQL / NoSQL TypeScript

Experience

Professional Freelancer

Developer and Designer - Feb 2015 to Present Professional freelance software developer and designer who specializes in website and mobile app development.

• Alpin

Frontend Developer Intern - May 2017 to Aug 2017
I was a frontend developer and lead graphic designer for a new application, Alpin.io. I worked with TypeScript and Angular 1 and 2.

Made Movement

iOS Developer Intern - Jun 2016 to Jul 2016
I created prototype iOS apps for clients, worked with Beacon technology, SceneKit, Cypress BLE devices, and a Raspberry Pi 3.

HackCU

Director and Lead Web Developer - Oct 2015 to Present
As director, I oversee sponsorship, logistics, technology,
hardware, and marketing. I was also the website and designer lead
for 2016.HackCU.org, 2017.HackCU.org and HackCU.org.

Lockheed Martin

Intern - Feb 2015 to Jun 2016

I worked with C#, ASP.net, and a SQL database to maintain a staff website. I currently hold a Secret clearance.

T9Hacks

Director - Oct 2015 to Mar 2016

T9Hacks is a women's technology event at CU Boulder aimed at increasing women participation in technology fields. I was one of the main event coordinators.

ASSETT

Technology Assistant - May 2014 to Dec 2014
I worked for the University of Colorado Boulder ASSETT team researching technology in university education.

Education

- University of Colorado Boulder
 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Graduating Dec 2017
- Front Range Community College
 Associates of Science Graduated May 2014
- Boulder High School
 High School Diploma Graduated May 2010